# **Bryan Stapleton**

# **Experienced Professional Looking for More**

Boulder, CO 80302 stapleton\_bryan@yahoo.com +1 408 348 0417

Experienced IT and business professional looking to make the jump into more development-focused role. 10 years of experience building and using computers as a power user; 2 years experience in product development; 2 years of experience with python back end development with Anaconda, Numpy, Flask, SQLAlchemy and NLTK3; 2 years of experience with front end technologies such as Vue and Bootstrap. Proficient in HTML/CSS, JavaScript and Python.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

# **Self Employed**

\_Flax - Boulder, CO

December 2021 to Present

Finished and Deployed a web application for data analysis named \_Flax.

- Built on a Flask back end, the application allows users to retrieve twitter data and analyze sentiment of tweets using NTLK3's VADER to be downloaded and/or fed into an ETL pipeline.
- Database in SQL with ORM handled by SQLAlchemy and Marshmallow.
- Front end in Vue with styling done in Bootstrap supplemented with custom CSS.
- Deployed on Heroku at https://flax-app.herokuapp.com/app

#### IT Support Specialist

Technology Helpers, LLC - Boulder, CO September 2021 to December 2021

- Supported 700+ configurations spanning 500+ end users across 16 clients alongside a small team of techs using the ConnectWise platform.
- Interfaced regularly with users to troubleshoot tech-related problems including cloud administration, Office 365, AD, deploying machines and basic networking problems such as DNS issues.
- Assisted in implementing standardization across internal documentation, improving accessibility of information and streamlining workflow.

#### **Founder**

303 CBD, LLC - Longmont, CO September 2017 to March 2020

- Designed and built manufacturing equipment for processing small batches of raw CBD.
- Manufactured and distributed several CBD products in Colorado and Texas under a wholly owned brand, "Exhempt".
- Developed branding, web presence and implemented KPI tracking to improve bounce rate on company website by 50% over 2-year period.
- Fostered strong relationships with suppliers and customers in both B2B and B2C capacities.

• Engaged in some light consulting to other firms in the hemp industry, primarily in the realm of manufacturing.

# **Assistant Manager**

Smackdaddy Pizza - Longmont, CO March 2016 to August 2017

- Opened and assisted owner with managing a small mom-and-pop shop.
- Supervised a team of 2-3 employees at a time.
- Filled roles as needed throughout the day, sometimes running the store alone.
- Maintained communication with the owner on logistics and escalated issues that I could not solve on rare occasion.
- Handled cash balancing and inventory daily.

#### **Administrative Assistant**

University of Colorado Boulder - Boulder, CO August 2012 to May 2014

- Served as the first point of contact for the Department of Continuing Education at CU Boulder.
- Greeted customers over the phone, engaged in light troubleshooting, and escalated issues to the appropriate heads of departments or advisors when necessary.
- Created, updated and maintained student records in CUSIS database management software.

#### Education

# **2 Years in Chemistry**

University of Colorado Boulder - Boulder, CO  $\,$ 

August 2012 to May 2014

# Skills

- Operating systems (10+ years)
- Customer service (7 years)
- Python (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- HTML5 (2 years)
- CSS (2 years)
- APIs (2 years)
- · Software Troubleshooting
- REST
- Cloud infrastructure
- SaaS
- AWS
- Git
- Node.js
- Bootstrap

- Linux
- GitHub
- SQL
- Vue.js
- ConnectWise
- React
- Product development

# Languages

- English Expert
- · Spanish Beginner
- Italian Beginner

#### Links

http://github.com/gljusty

### Certifications and Licenses

# **IT Support Professional Certificate**

September 2021 to Present

Completed a 5-part certification course covering operating systems, hardware, networking, security, troubleshooting and customer service.

https://www.credly.com/badges/4cf00abb-4c9b-4ecc-845a-f2515b097e0c/public\_url

# **Google IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate**

February 2022 to Present

Completed a 6-part course on automating IT processes in python including cloud management at scale, Git, interacting with the OS, and debugging techniques.

https://www.credly.com/badges/eaa1d0f9-eacd-440d-ac2e-b532d66aa39f/public\_url

### **Python 3 Specialization Certificate**

March 2022 to Present

Completed a 5-part specialization in Python 3 from the University of Michigan.

https://coursera.org/share/b0c48ecb2c0378a3c8dbfb69c25907c7

#### Assessments

# **Technical support — Highly Proficient**

September 2021

Performing software, hardware, and network operations

Full results: Highly Proficient

# Management & leadership skills: Planning & execution — Highly Proficient

October 2021

Planning and managing resources to accomplish organizational goals

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

# **Written communication — Expert**

November 2021

Best practices for writing, including grammar, style, clarity, and brevity

Full results: Expert

### **Analyzing data — Highly Proficient**

December 2021

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data Full results: Highly Proficient

# Typing — Expert

February 2022

Transcribing text Full results: Expert

### **Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Proficient**

February 2022

Knowledge of various Microsoft Excel features, functions, and formulas

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.